Edward ("Ted") Walther

http://warpedpuppy.com https://github.com/warpedpuppy tedwalther@gmail.com 415.902.2952

Software Developer with strong professional experience in the design, development and implementation of web sites, games and applications. Notable project-related experience includes:

- Conducted front-end web development of a website with traffic of 20 million monthly pageviews, and 1.7 billion monthly video views.
- Coded the redesign of a high-visibility website; integrated design specs from an NYC design firm with the CMS that created the skeleton of the site. Worked closely with the Head of Product to make sure that all design specifications were pixel-perfect and succeeded in having the design complete within the deadline.
- Worked for several years within a boiler-room game development environment during which my coding skills flourished. This experience nurtured my ability to plan, code, and de-bug quickly and efficiently.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript (VueJS, VueX, NuxtJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongooseJS, jQuery, UnderscoreJS, CreateJS, PixiJS, ReactJS, ReduxJS, Webpack), PHP, MySQL, AS3, HTML5, CSS, XML, and more

WEB PLATFORMS / FRAMEWORKS: LAMP & MEAN Stacks (including Hybrid), Bootstrap, Ajax, AWS, Netlify SOFTWARE DESIGN / DEVELOPMENT TOOLS: Intellij IDEA IDE, Git, Adobe Creative Suite, Sublime Text OPERATING SYSTEMS: Mac, Windows

DATABASES: MySQL, MongoJS

Professional Experience

ThinkFul, New York, New York (worked remotely) -- Coding Mentor

2017-present

- One on one mentoring in both web development fundamentals and full stack programming (Node and React)
- Guided students in creating advanced capstone web applications

CleverTech, New York, New York (worked remotely) -- Full Stack Developer 2017-2018

- Maintained an ecommerce site coded in VueJS and NuxtJS
- Coordinated the sites use of Shopify, Stripe, Mailchimp and Wordpress apis

The Dodo, New York, New York (worked remotely) -- Front-End Developer

2016-2017

- Wrote and maintained code for the entire front-end, and part of the back-end of the website.
- Worked directly with the Head of Product to create, edit and maintain site. Continually polished code to achieve optimized efficiency and operation.
- Collaborated with onshore and offshore development teams in the US and Europe, working to ensure that all teams effectively deliver software development requirements.
- Coded and implemented Google Analytics A/B experiments, which required creating alternate versions of the site. Edited and maintained Newsletter code with CampaignMonitor.com.
- Conducted all aspects of the software development lifecycle (SDLC), including requirements gathering, design specification, testing, and implementation to production environments.

Warped Puppy LLC, Ashland, Oregon -- Developer

2013-2016

- Designed, developed and maintained front-ends and back-ends for websites and mobile applications, providing operational and technical expertise during the creation and administration of sites.
- Supported best practices for ensuring efficient software development and support processes; created website enhancements according to customers' requirements.
- Analyzed and resolved inefficiencies in software platforms, and identified and capitalized on opportunities to develop and integrate transformative system improvements.
- Maintained JavaScript playground site http://tryingsomething.com.

Starfall Education, Boulder, CO (worked remotely) -- Software Engineer

2010-2013

- Programmed educational games for the website starfall.com, in particular the site's paid section more.starfall.com.
- Was the only on-staff full-time programmer and had to complete extremely complicated games quickly and efficiently.
- Collaborated with other designers to develop site assets and mobile applications that aligned with Starfall's highly particular development requirements.
- Created and implemented back-end strategies to support the web games, and developed dynamic web
 pages for the site.

Education

AcademyX -- San Francisco, CA

Two years of professional trade school focused in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL

Juris Doctor (J.D.) -- University of California, Hastings College of the Law

Passed both the California and Connecticut bars. Awarded an HPILF grant.

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) -- University of California Berkeley

Graduated with Honors